It's starting to look a little better.
大体 形にはなってきたかな
Want to take a break?
ちょっと休憩するか
Yeah, let's!
うん そうだな
Your cleaning skills are amazing.
阿良々木先輩の清掃スキルは目を見張るものがある
Perhaps I made my room messy
私は阿良々木先輩のそのスキルが見たくて
こうして部屋を散らかしているのかもしれないな
just so I could see your skill.
That'd be a pain, so please don't.
それは迷惑だから是非やめろ
阿良々木先輩は いいお嫁さんになる
You'll make a great wife.
なりたくねえ
I don't want to be one!
私の嫁に欲しいくらいだ
I'd almost want you as my wife...
いや 僕はお前が旦那ってのはいやだな
No,
I wouldn't want you for a husband.
結婚してくれるのでは
Then you'd marry me?
ポジションが逆ならな
Only if our positions were reversed.
どっちにしたってお前は戦場ヶ原に殺されるが
But either way, Senjougahara would kill you.
Well, she'd probably kill me too.
いや 多分僕も殺されるけど
Still, Araragi-senpai...
しかし阿良々木先輩 阿良々木先輩はあれだな
You and Senjougahara-senpai
make a good couple.
戦場ヶ原先輩とはお似合いのカップルではあるとは思うが
しかし最終的には羽川先輩と結婚しそうな感じがあるな
However,
I think you'll end up marrying Hanekawa-senpai.
Don't say that!
やなこと言うなよ
Also, you'll have me as a lover,
koyomi                 tsubasa
そして 私とは愛人関係
suruga
nadeko
千石ちゃんが三号か
and maybe Sengoku-chan as a third.
koyomi                 tsubasa
suruga
nadeko
Following that logic,
koyomi                 tsubasa
suruga
nadeko
koyomi                 tsubasa
suruga
nadeko
きっとその上 本命は八九寺なのだ
koyomi                 tsubasa
suruga
nadeko
koyomi                 tsubasa
suruga
nadeko
koyomi                 tsubasa
suruga
nadeko
koyomi                 tsubasa
suruga
nadeko
koyomi                 tsubasa
suruga
nadeko
koyomi                tsubasa
suruga
nadeko
koyomi                 tsubasa
suruga
nadeko
koyomi                 tsubasa
suruga
nadeko
koyomi                 tsubasa
suruga
nadeko
mayoi
I'm really in love with Hachikuji.
Th-That's not true...
そ…そんなことはないさ
I'm marrying Senjougahara someday.
僕は将来的に 戦場ヶ原と結婚するんだ
Cold Sweat
そんな夢見がちのプロポーズを私に対して今ここでされても挨拶に困るな
I don't know what to say
about your dream proposal.
But still, Araragi-senpai,
しかし実際 阿良々木先輩は
私が本気で迫ったら 断りきれないだろう
if I really pursued you, you couldn't refuse.
M-Marriage?
け…結婚をか
Nope.
いや
To be your mistress!
愛人関係を
I'd refuse!
断るよ
It's easy for girls to
阿良々木先輩の優しさは
女子から見れば付け込みやすいから気をつけたほうがよかろう という意味だ
take advantage of your kindness, so be careful.
That's what I mean.
For now, that's all it is.
まあ 今のところ他意はない
I like our current relationship.
私は今の関係が好きだから それを壊す方向へは動くつもりがないが
I wouldn't do anything to endanger it.
But should you ever hurt Senjougahara-senpai,
もしも阿良々木先輩が戦場ヶ原先輩を傷つけるようなことをしたら
きっと私はそのように動くのだろうな
I'm certain I would...
Actually, if I married Hanekawa,
ていうか 考えてみりゃ 羽川と結婚なんかしたら
羽川もまた戦場ヶ原に殺されちゃうじゃないか
wouldn't Senjougahara kill her too?
それは嫌だ 話さなかったか
I wouldn't want that.
Didn't I tell you?
I'm more grateful to Hanekawa than to anyone else.
僕は羽川を誰よりも恩人だと思ってるんだから
Well...
んー いや 羽川先輩
Hanekawa-senpai...
Hanekawa-senpai and Senjougahara-senpai...
羽川先輩と戦場ヶ原先輩の関係はな
Well, you don't need to worry about that relationship.
そういう心配はいらないと思うが
ああ なんだよ
Why?
They have their own little world, you know?
いや あの人達はあの人達で独自の世界があるからな
私としてはそれは不本意でもあるのだが
I'm not terribly pleased about the situation.
But since those two are happy with it,
しかし両者が納得している以上
少なくとも私が口を出せる筋合いではなかろう
it isn't my place to say anything.
Oh, Kanbaru...
あ そうだ神原 休憩時間の間に これやらないか
Wanna play this while we take a break?
Oh, Hanafuda!
shishinden
ああ 花札か…そう言えばあったな
I forgot I had that.
But I don't know the rules.
しかし 私はルールを解さん
デパートで売っているのを思いつきで買ってしまっただけだ
I just bought it on a whim at a department store.
なんだ そうなんだ じゃ無理か
Oh, I see...
Then we can't play.
No, that's not true, Araragi-senpai.
いや 無理と言うことはないぞ 阿良々木先輩
If you teach me, I can play!
教えてくれれば勿論できる
It may surprise you,
私はこう見えても 競技のルールを憶えるのは得意なほうだ
but I'm good at learning the rules to games.
What's wrong, Araragi-senpai?
どうした阿良々木先輩 阿良々木先輩が親だぞ
You're the parent this round.
Sorry...
いやごめん 手四
I've got a four-hand.
That's six points.
六文なんだけと
Koyomi       Suruga
So, yeah...
じゃあそんなわけで 珍しい役も出たところで 終わりにしようか
That was a rare hand, so let's end it here.
待てこの があ
Wait! Darn it...
We still have one match left.
あと一回戦残っている
Don't get so mad...
そんなムキになるなよ ブレスレット ブレスレット
Bracelet! Bracelet!
It's just a game.
こんなの たかが遊びだろ
そんな志の低さでどうして勝てる
How can you win without taking it seriously?
But I am winning.
いや 僕は勝ってるじゃん
遊びなんだから 楽しむってことも必要だぜ
It's just a game.
You should enjoy it...
For example, look at Sengoku.
千石なんてみてみろ
あいつにツイスターゲームって遊びを教えてもらったんだがな
She taught me something called "Twister."
She lost to a total newbie like me,
初心者の僕に負けたところで あいつはすごく楽しそうだったぞ
but she still seemed really happy.
Araragi-senpai,
阿良々木先輩は どうやら真のラスボスの存在に
it seems you've not yet recognized
まだ気付いていないようだな
the true final boss's existence.
あ なんの話だ
What are you talking about?
何でもない それも私が口を出すようなことではないのだ
Nothing.
It's not my place to say anything.
Kanbaru?
神原
なんだ 阿良々木先輩
What is it, Araragi-senpai?
We should decide on a punishment game first.
罰ゲームを先に決めておくぞ
You're certainly in a hurry.
気が早いな ちなみに私の側からは性的な欲求
I intend to ask for a sexual pact...
否 性的な要求をするつもりだぞ
I mean, I'll ask for a sexual act.
そうか いや 死ねでもいいよ
I see.
You can order me to die if you want.
Never, ever, start gambling!
お前は生涯ギャンブルをするな
Continuing on, the younger little sister. Araragi Tsukihi. Middle school second-year.
Birthday at the beginning of April. Now fourteen years old. Unlike the older fire sister, Tsukihi's hairstyle changes based on her mood and the season.
That she would not stay with the same hairstyle for three months conversely makes it unclear if she has any preference.
She had straight long hair until just a while ago, but now it's a shaggy dutch bob.
As I wasn't interested, I didn't ask for details, but apparently, she has a favorite salon.
It's not that I don't think she's conceited for a middle-schooler, but in this day and age, that might just be how it is.
However, in Tsukihi's case, the problem is not so much external as it is indeed internal.
No matter what Karen may say, she's the same inside as she is outside, but Tsukihi's appearance betrays her character. It's key that her character isn't betraying her appearance.
In contrast with her sister, Tsukihi has docile, drooping eyes, a short build that's the absolute opposite of Karen,
and a measured tone of voice that's truly like that of a girl's, but on the inside, she's more aggressive than Karen, and worse, she's hot-tempered.
After Karen committed some mayhem, I listened carefully at the circumstances behind it, and not once or twice I found that it all originated from Tsukihi.
She is so hot-tempered that it may already be called hysteria.
People around her are always bewildered by her gentle appearance and this gap.
Well, if she has one saving grace, it's that she consistently only gets angry for the sake of someone else.
To refer to a particular episode, this was back when Tsukihi was a second-year in elementary school.
A soccer ball that some upperclassmen were playing with came flying into the garden where her class was growing sunflowers during recess.
The classmate in charge of watering the plants scolded the upperclassmen who came to retrieve the ball, but their high-handed talk back made him cry.
Well, it's not something unusual in a elementary school, but hearing this, Tsukihi acted swiftly,
located in an instant the class those upperclassmen belonged to, and charged into their classroom (Karen was with her, by the way).
The turmoil, subsequently commemorated as the Ikedaya Incident (just because there was a Shinsengumi boom at the time, no real meaning behind this naming),
didn't end just with one upperclassman to be hospitalized, and the furnishings of the classroom almost completely destroyed.
Not satisfied, they went at length, sending sunflowers as a get-well gift to the hospitalized upperclassman.
Karen Bee Part 3
Episode 3
Type Font Used HGP Minchou B
I asked Kanbaru about something I'd been wondering...
僕は神原に 気になっていたことを訊いた
What she tells her family
つまり その左腕のことを家族にはどう説明しているのか である
about her left arm.
I tell them it's injured.
怪我で通しているよ
とてもではないが 説明できるものではないしな
I don't think it's something I could really explain.
But does that work?
でもそれで通るか
Unlike my vampirism,
僕の吸血鬼体質とは違って お前の左腕は見たらわかるもんだろう
your left arm is something they can see.
Well, my grandma and grandpa
まあ それは勿論お祖父ちゃんもお祖母ちゃんも
私のことを心配してくれてはいるがな
worry about me, naturally.
But despite everything, what happened with
それでも私と彼らの間には どうしようもなく母親のことがある
my mother puts a wall between me and them.
So they never ask anything
だから 私が踏み込んでほしくないところには
I wouldn't want them to ask.
あの人たちは決して踏み込まないのさ
Either way, I only have to tolerate it
ま どちらにしてもあと数年の我慢だ
for a few more years.
Are you a child from this household?
お前はこの家の子供かな
No...
いえ
Actually, I'm not.
違います…けれど
I apologize.
ああ すまない 名乗り忘れたな
I haven't introduced myself.
The caution you've shown a total stranger is very appropriate.
見ず知らずの人間に対するその警戒は酷く正しい 大切にするがいい
Treasure it.
My name is Kaiki.
俺は貝木と言う
カイキ
Kaiki?
Yes.
そう 貝塚の貝に 枯れ木の木だ
"Kai," as in a mound of clamshells.
"Ki," as in a dead tree.
My name is Araragi.
僕は阿良々木です
The kanji are, uh...
漢字は えっと
No need to explain.
そこまで説明しなくていい
It's a name I understand already.
それは聞いたばかりの名だ
ただし 俺が枯れ木だとすれば
But I suppose if I'm a dead tree,
お前は若木なのだろうがな
you must be a sapling.
Well, if you need something at Kanbaru's place...
その もしも神原の家に用なんでしたら
うむ お前は最近の若者にしては礼儀正しいな
You're polite for a child these days.
それに気遣いの出来る男だ 面白い
And kind too. Interesting.
ただし 俺に関してはそこまでの気遣いは無用だ
But your kindness is wasted on me.
この家にも特に用があったというわけではない ただし
And I have no particular business with this household.
However...
I've heard that the Gaen child lives here.
臥煙の女の忘れ形見がここで暮らしているという話を聞いてしまったのでな
何をするわけでもないが 少し様子を見てみようと思っただけだ
I don't have anything to do here, but I thought I might take a look.
That's all.
Gaen?
臥煙
Isn't that the maiden name of Kanbaru's mother?
確か 神原の母親の旧姓だったか
Then her child would be Kanbaru Suruga?
忘れ形見とは ならば神原駿河のことか
But I've wasted my time.
しかし無駄足だったな
I hardly feel any aura at all.
ほとんどオーラを感じない およそ三分の一と言ったところだな
One-third, I'd say...
これならば放置しておいていいだろう
It won't cause problems if I ignore it.
いや 放置しておくしかあるまい
No, I have no choice but to ignore it.
残念ながら 金にはならん
Unfortunately, there's no money to be made.
The lesson for me here is that
今回の件から俺が得るべき教訓は
even if the truth is as one suspects,
真実など たとえ思い通りであったところで
it may still be worthless.
場合によってはくだらないということだ
Um...
えっと
No...
いや あのだらしねえ忍野とじゃ 全然違うんだけどな
He's totally different from that slacker, Oshino.
He was more like Guillotine Cutter.
それよりは
ギロチンカッター
Well, both Oshino and Guillotine Cutter
まあ 忍野とギロチンカッターも 全然違うタイプだけど
were totally different types, but...
I'll follow him.
追うか
Maybe it's intuition,
直感だが 何だかあの男と関わるのはまずい気がする
but I feel like getting involved with him is a bad idea.
縁起の悪い 辛気臭い喪服
Those were strange, depressing funerary clothes.
But there was something far beyond that...
しかし それはそんなレベルではなく
ただ 不吉なのであった
Something ominous.
不吉 それは
Ominous...
and threatening.
THREAT
凶という意味だ
Hey! Senjougahara!
おい 戦場ヶ原
って
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
マジでへこむことすんなや
Don't do things that will depress me!
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
お おい 戦場ヶ原
Hey, Senjougahara.
I don't know any boy who'd neglect his studies,
勉強もせずにこんなところをふらふらしているような男のことを
just to wander around here.
私は知らない
Well... Y-You've misunderstood.
あ いや
ご 誤解だって
Silence. I most certainly have not.
WARNING
だまらっしゃい 誤解もお蚕様もないわ
Running from my tutelage is one thing, but to run from Hanekawa-san's,
私の授業からならばともかく
羽川さんの授業から逃げ出すなんて腑抜けにも程があるわね
you must be an utter coward.
I'm disappointed in you.
失望しました
No, no.
違う違う 羽川が今日は忙しいらしくって
Hanekawa's busy today and couldn't make it.
お休みなんだよ
I'm tired of excuses, incompetent fool.
言いわけは聞き飽きたわ この無能が
WARNING
In the end, you're all talk, Araragi-kun.
所詮あなたは口だけの男というわけね 阿良々木君
The fact that a man like you won my heart
あなたのような男に心を奪われたことは
私にとって一生の恥よ
will shame me for the rest of my life.
You say things that would drive any other man to suicide
お前 僕じゃなかったら自殺するようなことを当たり前のように言うよな
like it's nothing, you know?
はっ 虫が
Insect.
WARNING
ガハラさん ガハラさん
Gahara-san! Gahara-san!
What is it, Churaragi-kun?
何よ ちゅらら木君
Don't say my name like
an obscure regional Okinawa word!
人の名前を沖縄県の方言みたいに呼ぶな
僕の名前は阿良々木だ
My name is Araragi!
And that's Hachikuji's gag!
って そりゃ八九寺の芸風だろうが
Sorry! I bit my tongue.
失礼 噛みました
No, you did it deliberately.
違う わざとだ
I bit my tongue, and you can die.
噛みま死ね
She really did do it deliberately!
やっぱわざとだ
Don't get the wrong idea.
勘違いしないでよね
I actually hate human garbage like you.
私は本当は阿良々木君みたいな人間の屑のことは大嫌いなんだから
Are you just taking advantage of your tsundere status
お前 ツンデレっていう設定にかこつけて
ひょっとしてただの本音を語ってないか
to say what you really think?!
But they say a woman's better off
ただ 女は愛する男より
愛されない男と一緒になったほうが幸せだって言うから
with an unloved man, versus a man who loves her.
That isn't quite right!
U
N
L
O
V
E
D
M
A
N
微妙に違うし
WARNING
It's a joke.
冗談よ
Everyone loves you, and you're super popular.
阿良々木君は愛されまくりのモテまくりだもんね
WATCH
YOUR
STEP
WATCH YOUR HEAD
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
WARNING
DANGER ZONE
DANGER
Let's see...
じー 三人 いえ 五人かしら
Three. Or is it five?
Wh-What's that?
な 何がですか
The number of girls you've played with today.
本日阿良々木君が遊んだ女子の数
One
Two
Three
Four
Five
厳密に言えば 六人
To be completely accurate, six.
Six
Grandma
So, with that in the open,
DANGER ZONE
DANGER
で そういう予想を立てた上で改めて
everyone loves you, and you're super popular.
阿良々木君は愛されまくりのモテまくりだもんね
Don't worry, Araragi-kun.
DANGER ZONE
DANGER
安心していいわよ 阿良々木君
私はこう見えて 浮気には結構寛容なのよ
I may not seem it,
but I'm quite tolerant regarding adultery.
う 浮気なんてしてませんが
I'm not committing adultery.
ぼ 僕がしているのは浮き輪くらいのものですよ
I'm not even engaging in the "adult" part.
So regardless, of what or whom you play with,
だから 誰とどんな風に遊ぼうと
it is your choice.
それは阿良々木君の自由だけれど
その浮気が少しでも本気になったなら
But if it ever gets the slightest bit serious,
I'll kill you.
殺すわよ
DANGER ZONE
DANGER
Don't worry.
大丈夫 阿良々木君ひとりを死なせたりなんかしない
I won't let you die alone.
I'll send the other woman right after you.
あとから相手の女も送ってあげるわ
Why won't you die with me too?
だからお前が死ねよ
Then I'll send Kanbaru, so you won't get lonely!
その後 寂しくないよう神原を派遺してあげる
What do you think Kanbaru is?
お前は神原を何だと思ってるんだ
都合のいい後輩
An underclassman I can use however I like.
A cruel definition stated without hesitation!
迷いなく残酷な定義
WARNING
It's a joke.
冗談よ 神原は可愛い後輩
Kanbaru is my cute little underclassman.
それにそもそも私は死後の世界なんて
And I don't believe in life after death.
これっぽっちも信じてはいないんだけれどね
I see...
あっそう
I just wanted you to understand
ただ 私と付き合うということはそういうことだと
that this is what it means to date me.
阿良々木君にはわかっておいて欲しかっただけ
N
O
E
N
T
R
I get it.
わかってるよ
I wouldn't cheat, anyway.
そもそも 浮気なんてしない
Okay.
あらそう ならいいわ
Very well, then.
WARNING
As long as you don't forget to whom you belong,
阿良々木くんが 自分が一体誰の男なのかを忘れていなければ
私はそれでいいのよ
that's fine.
I put a decent amount of effort into being your woman.
私は阿良々木君の女であるために それなりに努力している
できれば阿良々木君にも 同じようにして欲しいと思うわ
If possible, I'd like you to do the same.
Effort, huh?
努力ね
I am...
してるさ 自分が誰の男かなんて 忘れたことねえよ
I've never forgotten to whom I belong.
I see...
あらそう
DANGER ZONE
DANGER
By the way, Araragi-kun,
ちなみに阿良々木君 それはそれとして
that said, I'd like to be certain that you know this...
最後に参考までに言わせてもらうけれど
Speaking as a girlfriend, it's actually quite wonderful
自分の彼氏がモテモテと言うのは
彼女として 割と最高の気分なのよ
to have such a popular boyfriend.
Too close to what she's really thinking!
本音過ぎるわ
Are you going somewhere?
どっか行く途中なのか
I finished my shopping, so I'm heading home.
買い物を終えて家に帰る途中よ
Speaking of which, what are you doing out here?
ところで阿良々木君のほうはどうしてこんなところに
ここはあなたのテリトリーではないでしょう
This isn't your normal territory.
Can't you tell?
見てわからないか
残念ながら私は微生物の行道学は学んでないわ
Unfortunately, I've never studied the actions of microscopic organisms.
But if I had to guess regardless, given what I know about you,
それでもあえて予想するなら
そうね 阿良々木君のことだから 軽犯罪の帰り
I'd say you're returning from some misdemeanor.
Do you think I just go out and commit crimes?
そんなブラリ散歩気分で軽犯罪を犯すか
神原の家に行った帰りだよ
I'm on my way back from Kanbaru's.
そう 神原の家で軽犯罪を
I see.
You were committing misdemeanors at Kanbaru's.
犯してねえ
I was not!
Oh?
あら てっきり神原の裸でも見てきたのかと思った
I thought you saw Kanbaru naked.
I... I did not!
み 見てねえ
At least not from the front.
いや 正面からは見てない
言うまでもないと思ってそんな細かい説明を省略しただけなのだ
I simply thought a minor detail like that wasn't worth sharing.
Come to think of it,
ああ そういや
I saw a weird guy in front of Kanbaru's house.
神原の家の前で変な奴を見たぜ
Oh?
え いつから神原の家の前に鏡が設置されたの
When did they hang a mirror in front of her house?
He was strange...
変な奴っつーか 不吉な奴なんだけど
Kind of sinister.
不吉
Sinister?
His name was...
名前は
Kaiki?
貝木っつったっけ
I think.
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Five
Four
Three
Two
One
7/30
Early
Morning
Animation Number 229
Do you know this Kaiki guy?
貝木って男
お前の知り合いなのか
聞かないでくれるとありがたいんだけれど
I'd prefer that you not ask.
If I shouldn't, then I won't.
そうするべきなら そうするけれど
でもそうじゃないだろ
But that isn't really the case, is it?
If you have to do all this...
お前がここまでしなきゃならないんだから
It was just to protect me.
僕を守るため
NO ENTRY
Entry Without Permission is Prohibited
Private Property
Illegal Dumping is Prohibited
Absolutely
No
LITTERING
D
A
N
G
E
R
O
U
S
NO   ENTRY
NO
ENTRY
LOOK OUT FOR GAPS
Safety
Foreign Construction(Ltd.)
Personnel Only
Hazardous
Senjougahara kidnapped me
僕を守りたくて 戦場ヶ原は僕を拉致監禁しているのだから
NO ENTRY
in order to protect me.
Emergency Alarm
Press Hard
For you to go to these lengths,
お前がここまでするなんて ただごとじゃない
it must be a big deal.
You think so?
そう 私 相手が阿良々木君なら
Personally, I'd say that it's likely
拉致監禁くらい理由がなくとも口実さえあれば
that I'd kidnap you
without even the slightest of pretexts.
平気でしそうだけれど
Yeah...
貝木泥舟
Kaiki Deishuu.
That's his name.
その男の名前よ
貝木なんてそうある名前でもないし
Kaiki is an uncommon name.
それに不吉だというなら間違いないわ
If you saw him and "sinister" sprang to mind,
that's him.
あれほど不吉という言葉が似合う男を
I know no other man who suits
that term so well.
私は他に知らない
Yes,
そう 阿良々木君が何も知らないように
just as you know nothing at all...
I never imagined he'd return to this town...
まさかこの町に戻ってきていたなんてね
Surprising, inexplicable...
意外というか不可解というか
実際思いもしなかったわ
Honestly, I didn't expect it in the slightest.
What's he like?
どういう奴なんだ
It's unusual for you to have such animosity for someone.
お前がそこまで毛嫌いする相手なんて珍しい
貝木は詐欺師よ
Kaiki is a fraud.
You and Oshino-san solved my problem,
私の抱えていた問題については 阿良々木君
それに忍野さんに解決してもらったわよね
as I'm sure you recall.
Yeah.
And did I not tell you?
で 言わなかったっけ
How, before you introduced me to Oshino-san,
阿良々木君に忍野さんを紹介してもらう前に
I met with five con men.
私は五人の詐欺師に出会っている
Kaiki was one of them.
貝木はその内の一人 最初の一人よ
The first.
I understand.
なるほど
His feel was akin to that of Oshino and Guillotine Cutter.
忍野と それにギロチンカッターと似た匂いがあったはずだ
Those two are similar due to their supernatural expertise.
二人とも 怪異に対する専門家という点では同じだ
And Kaiki...
そして 貝木
Kaiki Deishuu is just like them.
貝木泥舟も また同じ
Regardless of whether he's for real or a fake...
それが本物か偽物かはともかくとして
He's a fake,
偽物よ
but he's a master con man.
ただし 詐欺師としては一流だった
My entire family and I have suffered greatly at his hands.
私はね あの男に家族ごと酷い目に遭わされたのよ
He did a few tricks, took our money,
いろいろやったあげく お金だけ巻き上げて
and vanished without helping at all.
結局は何もせずに姿を消したわ
But that's a minor issue.
けれど そんなのは些細なことなのよ
So, what isn't minor?
じゃあ 些細じゃないことは何だよ
I do not
私は 阿良々木君にあの男と関わって欲しくないの
want you involved with him.
That's all.
それだけなのよ
I will no longer relinquish that which is important to me.
私はもう二度と大事なものを手放さない
I won't lose anything else.
なくしたくない だから
Therefore,
I am going to protect you, Araragi-kun.
だから 阿良々木君は
私が守る
Is this Kaiki that much of a problem?
貝木って奴は そんなに問題があるのか
Why do you want me to stay away?
どうして僕に会わせたくないと思うんだ
そうね 正義マンの阿良々木君には刺激の強過ぎる相手よ
Hmm...
he's too much for a man of justice like yourself.
正義マンって
"A man of justice"?
ファイヤーシスターズじゃあるまいし
I'm not one of the Fire Sisters.
Until I at least know what he's after
少なくとも貝木の目的がわかるまで
and why he's returned,
何をしにこの町に戻って来たのかがわかるまで
I'd like you to please remain here.
阿良々木君はここで大人しくしておいてちょうだい
No.
いいえ たとえ貝木に目的なんてものがなかったとしても
Even if he isn't here for any specific reason,
I'd like you to stay here until he leaves.
あの男が町を出るまで 阿良々木君にはここにいて欲しいわね
What if he moves here?
もしも貝木がこの町に引っ越して来たんだったら
If he moves here...
そのときは
Then you'll spend the rest of your life in this room.
阿良々木君は一生ここで過ごす
おい ガハラさん
Hey, Gahara-san!
それか
Or...
I could kill Kaiki.
貝木を殺すか
いや
Wait.
そうね
I know. I'll go "click" on him.
じゃあ 貝木をパチンとするか
パチンって 可愛い擬音で表現しても駄目
"Click"?
Cute sounds do not make it okay!
Not      Okay
駄目なものは駄目
And it isn't okay!
Not      Okay
Not       Okay
大体貝木って男はどんな
Anyway, what is this Kaiki guy...
Can I get that?
見ていいか
Wait, you're groping around too much!
って いやいや まさぐり過ぎだろ
どさくさにまぎれてどこ触ってるんだ
Where are you touching me?
It's hard to reach deep in your pocket.
奥のほうにあってうまく取り出せないのよ
My pockets aren't that deep.
僕のポケットはそんなに深くないよ
I see.
そう 阿良々木君は人生もポケットも深くないのね
Neither your life nor your pockets are that deep, right?
Do you have to hurt me just to find my cell phone?
傷つけられなきゃ携帯電話も取り出してもらえないのかよ
Younger Little
Sister
From:
Subject: Help me
Younger Little
Sister
Subject: Help me
Araragi-kun?
阿良々木君
Where are you going?
どこへ行く気
I have somewhere I need to be.
野暮用ができた 遊びはここまでだ
That's enough playing around.
Sorry, but I'm going home.
悪いが僕は家に帰る
Do you think you can?
帰れると思う
I do. It's my home.
帰るさ 僕の家だ
And my family.
Koyomi Voice /Dialogue
Animation Number 327
そして 僕の家族だ
Just so we're clear,
言っておくけれど
I'm not such a coward that I'd hesitate to face a vampire.
私は相手が吸血鬼だからといって怯むほど臆病じゃないし
Nor kind enough to hesitate because I'm facing my lover.
相手が恋人だからといって怯むほど優しくもないわよ
I know.
知ってるよ
That's why I like you.
だからお前が好きなんだ
If you want to get past me, you'll have to defeat me.
ここを通りたければ私を倒すしかないわよ
Can you do that?
阿良々木君にそれができるかしら
通るよ
I can.
その台詞はブリッジして言わなければ効果がない
Those lines don't work unless they're said together.
Just as you claim to wish to protect me,
お前が僕を守りたいと言ってくれるように
僕にも守りたいものはあるんだ
I have something I want to protect.
Do you expect those words to convince me?
そんな言葉で私を説得できるとでも
説得する必要なんかねえだろ
They don't need to, right?
I don't know about that.
さあ どうかしら
I'd prefer you not consider me a tolerant type of woman.
私のことをあまり理解のある女だとは思わないで欲しいわね
But, Senjougahara...
でも 戦場ヶ原
だったらお前 僕のどこに惚れたんだ
What was it that made you fall in love with me?
Can you boldly claim to love me even if I do nothing now?
ここで動かない僕を お前は好きだと誇れるのか
Oh, no.
やば 超格好いい
That's really cool.
If I were a man, I'd love you.
私が男だったら恋してるわ
Stay a woman and love me anyway!
女のままで恋しろよ
I do.
してるけど
Hello?
もしもし 今取り込み中よ
I'm busy right now.
N-No...
い いえ
それは誤解よ
That's a misunderstanding...
そんなこと一言も言っていないでしょう
I never said a word about that.
ちょっと待って そんなことはしなくていい
Wait a second...
You don't have to do that.
約束が違うわ
That wasn't the deal.
やめて お願いよ 猶予をちょうだい
Stop, please...
Give me some time.
All right.
わかりました 全部あなたの言う通りにするわ
I'll do everything you say.
You can go home, Araragi-kun.
帰っていいわよ 阿良々木君
いいのか 本当に
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
いいわよ
A-And Araragi-kun...
そ その 阿良々木君 なんていうか あれなんだけれど
Well, you know...
I'm s-sor... I'm sorry...
ご ごめ ごめんなさい
あのさ ガハラさん
Hey, Gahara-san?
Who were you talking to by the way?
ちなみに 今の電話の相手って 誰だったの
White Scene
Animation Number "None"
To be continued.
羽川さん
Hanekawa-san.
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Hey! I'm Kanbaru Suruga!
We're the fire sisters!
They call me Massuruga because of my preferences,
and, well, I guess I'm fine with that.
Everyone has an idiotic part of them that thinks duffle coats are used to muffle sound,
Kanbaru-san
Are you wandering around
at night?
Wha?
delicatessen a way of being delicate,
or paralegals a kind of obscure crime.
She wants to stay
for some reason.
Rotten
Now, I don't wish put myself in the limelight,
but I'm the only one in the vast world of basketball who thought Corchorus was really great cork.
She's strong!
Rotten
By the way, what does limelight have to do with limes?
The hell is this?
Rattling
Wha!
Do you own a citrus farm or something?
Next time! Karen Bee, Part 4!
Next Time
Karen Bee Part 4
Did you get your
BL novels early?
Rotten
Don't pull an all-nighter.
On second thought, don't call me Massuruga.